Podcasting 2.0 for December 12th, 2025,
episode 244, Open Source Royalty.
Everybody, ho, ho, ho, ho.
We're getting closer.
We're getting closer to
Christmas, the end of the year.
Oh, man, but that doesn't
matter because there's
still podcasting going on everywhere.
This is the board meeting where
we discuss all things podcasting,
the inner workings, the guts, if you will.
Do you have a healthy gut biome?
We are the only boardroom that
does not require an entry fee.
I'm Adam Curry, here in the heart of
the Texas Hill Country, and in Alabama,
the man who has the code in
his hand and built the land.
Say hello to my friend on the other
end, the one, the only, Mr. Dave.
I got a Christmas bonus
in the mail from you.
It arrived. Have you opened it
yet? You left it in this gift bag.
No, I took it out of the bag. It will make
the meat this Christmas very enjoyable.
Let me tell you, this thing is amazing.
Really? This is like a Wi-Fi.
Yeah, it's two probes.
Probe, yeah.
Yeah, two probes. Of course, it
comes with an app, of course.
You jam those probes.
So China can track your brisket.
Oh, yeah. No, your brisket
is tracked for sure.
Okay.
Yeah, and the base unit,
actually, that has a battery,
so you need to make sure that's charged.
And then it, in turn, charges the probes.
So once you've gone through the very easy
process of pairing everything and getting
your base unit to talk to the Wi-Fi.
That's going to work
flawlessly from the beginning.
Flawlessly. Not a problem.
All my friends said, oh, so easy.
And so then you just stick
those thermometers in.
Probe it, yeah.
Yeah, the probes.
Now, you set the, on the
app, you set the start.
And just ignore everything.
Just select beef, smoker, and
then the temperature you want.
And it's amazing.
Now, it's going to tell you a lot of
things like, time to take it off.
Just do whatever you want to do.
But your internal temperature
will be spot on correct.
I've been enjoying this
for the past six weeks.
It is fantastic.
Thank you, brother.
You're more than welcome.
Of course.
That was unexpected.
I was not expecting meat, you
know, like meat improvement.
Hardware.
I have not received my physical
product from your gift yet.
You have.
Don't worry.
I'm going to have to call them.
I knew this was going to happen.
Do you have any idea what it is?
No, because I decided not
to look at the email.
No, of course not.
I'm going to have, I knew
this was going to happen.
I'm going to have to call them.
I don't know how long it's going to take
for them to ship you the physical version.
Brother, brother, the love that you
even did that is all I need, man.
It's all I need.
I send out, I send out gifts to
people in the podcast world.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
I'm not the only one.
What?
You send out gifts to other people too?
A few.
I thought I was special.
Well, you were special in the beginning.
Then I expanded my reach.
Oh, the speciality expanded.
I see what happened here.
I had to grow.
You had to grow your specialty.
Yeah, I had to grow my podcast.
Yeah, I had to grow my show.
It's just, there's so many people
that are so, that are so kind.
It's just like, it's hard not to send
something at this special time of year.
Have you noticed how many
podcast award shows there are?
I mean, this is out of control.
We need one.
Well, it's funny you say that
because as I was thinking, you know,
now the Golden Globes, you can win
a podcast for the Golden Globes.
$500 entrance fee, I might add.
Oh, is that?
Yeah, that's how that works.
It's not minor.
That's, you know, that's
pretty significant.
And it's always, it's, you
know, it's always, you know,
people have big downloads or
with Spotify or Sirius XM.
Oh, that show's great.
And then we have the Podcast Hall of Fame.
I don't want to disparage
it, but I'm going to.
It's like, okay, it's like,
you know, it's like, I mean,
I was in the first Hall of
Fame and I felt like I died.
You know, it's like, who wants to be?
That's where Go Podcasting came from.
Yeah.
That is where that clip, isn't that right?
That is exactly, well, the
mic drop was added later.
That's exactly where it came from.
And as I was thinking, as always, the unsung
heroes are right here in the boardroom.
The people who make it work.
We've got the podcast hosting companies.
We've got app developers.
We've got, you know, a merry band of
misfits and cretins running around,
ourselves included, all
just trying to do stuff.
And over the past five years, we have
actually made some things happen.
Things have moved.
You know, there is now
another, people actually,
the namespace is declared
in almost every RSS feed,
whether the tags are added or
not, the namespace is declared.
That's kind of an important win.
We've got Apple adding tags that
were developed in this group.
We are regrouping on Lightning payments.
And, you know, we developed, you know, the
pushing HLS video, alternate enclosure.
And we need something, we
need something for us.
And you, you know, I'm serious.
We need something.
I agree.
And I was thinking, like, if I just, I
would just think about this for a second.
I'm like, whoa.
What would an award show
look like for the index?
You know?
And, like, well, we'd have a
theater of the mind, obviously.
Oh, yeah, of course.
Now, we don't want a
whole bunch of judges.
We don't want crowd to judge,
you know, because, hold on,
let me bring the crowd in for a second.
We don't want them to be voting.
You know, I think, basically, you and I
should be in charge of this thing, you know?
This crowd clearly does not have
those headphones on that are colored.
No, no, none of these dumb headphones.
This thing is open, loud, and proud.
And, you know, what
else should we call it?
You know, we don't want to call it
the potties or anything like that.
No, we're going to call
it the Index Awards.
And I think.
No, I thought you were instead
of the Podcast Hall of Fame.
No, no.
You were going to go with
the Podcast Hall of Justice.
Tonight, only open podcasting matters.
Oh, my gosh.
It's the Index Awards.
Hear the applause for those who
fought the gatekeeper's iron laws.
You coded the tags.
You implemented the specs.
No more value missing from your checks.
From lightning to keys, send to LNURL.
From transcripts to chapters, the
podcasting 2.0 is catching its adapters.
We're thanking the devs who
make the fees flow free.
And gave us podcasts.
Location for all the world to see.
Introducing the judges.
But every show needs room.
True.
Who know what to do.
No hundred critics.
No votes from the crowd.
Just two legends whose names ring out.
Today is what we're here to see.
Don't raise up your mic.
Give us your hand a cone.
Forget the old song.
It wrote you in.
Big finish.
We're this world.
What if you're done?
What the heck was that?
Where did that come from?
It's AI, clearly.
I mean, like...
Okay, so you're...
It's just hard to believe.
I should...
Okay.
Let me tell you the prompt
I gave it for the lyrics.
Obviously, it was Suno.
No, Chad F. said, this song is all the
effort that will be put into this.
Oh, yes.
No, obviously.
100% true.
No, that's obvious.
Uh-huh.
Let me see if I can find the...
No, see, instead of the...
Instead...
Okay.
I've got tears.
Instead of the...
Instead of the Podcast Hall of Fame, it
needs to be the Podcast Hall of Justice.
You know...
Hold on.
So, here's what I put into Gemini.
Because I literally just threw it
into Gemini, and here was the prompt.
Write lyrics for a bombastic
award show opening number
for a new award show
from the Podcast Index.
The Index Awards for short.
Everything else, all of the
lyrics came out of Gemini.
That was your entire prompt?
That was the entire prompt.
Oh, my gosh.
I had to fix a few things,
because it didn't really understand
how to pronounce L-N-U-R-L.
Of course not.
But that was it.
And then, you know, I just spent...
Here's how you spell it.
D-D-O-S.
That's how you spell L-N-U-R-L.
And then I probably regenerated about 10
times, you know, adjusting a few things.
You didn't give it any URLs.
You didn't give it anything.
Just that.
That's it.
That was it.
It knew about the Index.
It knew about you.
It knew about me.
Really?
Yes.
All of that stuff.
Yeah.
How is this possible?
I don't know.
But when that happened, I'm like,
okay, now I got to get crowd sound.
Now I got to get the tension music.
I've got to get my little
dream sequence, you know?
Well, man, this is...
I'm a little bit...
I'm kind of speechless.
That's so...
I can't believe that...
Of course, bombastic,
that was your key word.
Yeah, of course.
That made the whole thing go.
That was the gasoline in the engine.
Yes.
Yeah.
I can't believe that it
was able to glean...
Is there...
Where is it getting the fact that...
Pod news.
It's all coming from pod news.
It sucks pod news into the entire corpus.
What else could it be?
Oh, yeah.
That's got to be it.
Mm-hmm.
Yeah.
That's got to be it.
But I...
You know...
Yeah, that's got to be it.
Because I can't imagine that
it's going to even find
association of you and
I to podcast in this.
Because we're not even on the site.
No, but it pulled in all these tags, too.
Location tag, chapters, transcripts.
It pulled all that stuff in.
I didn't tell it to do tags.
I didn't...
That's the prompt I gave it.
And that's what came out.
I'm like, I'm not changing a thing.
Like, I'm just going to...
Of course not.
That's effort.
Because, you know, if you actually say,
well, could you make it this or that?
Then it ruins it.
The minute you try to
iterate, it's no good.
It's no good.
It breaks.
Yeah.
Everything gets worse.
It just entropes itself.
Yes.
Which is interesting because I heard...
What was...
There was some dude...
Let me see.
Yeah.
Some dude, Nate Soros.
And he wrote a book, If Anyone
Builds It, Everyone Dies.
Who?
Yeah, about AI.
And let me see if this is the clip.
As you know, many of your
critics have said that
this is more like science
fiction than science.
Let me just see if this is the clip.
One of the problems with Stephen Marsh,
for example, in the New York Times.
Yeah, we do actually define the
terms in the book if he had read.
He was, Stephanopoulos was saying, how
much time do we have before we all die?
Thanks to Jay for that.
We're joined now by...
No, that's not it.
Where is it?
It's really good if I
can ever get this five.
Here it is, I think.
How much time do we have?
Here we go.
You know, the timing is very hard to call.
It could be that next year, the
AIs will still be pretty dumb,
but they'll be just barely
smart enough to make smarter AIs that
make smarter AIs that make smarter AIs.
So when I heard that, the
first thing I said is no.
No, that goes against entropy.
That goes against the law, the
second law of thermodynamics.
AI will create a dumber AI or a worse AI.
It cannot create better.
It just, that doesn't happen.
Yeah, I think there's,
so I've actually had talks about
this with a few different people
this week about other AI related topics,
but we had, I was, I was listening to,
I was listening to Windows Weekly and
I heard a big discussion about this.
And so you, you hear a lot of, you hear
this argument that AI is additive,
you know, that it's not, that
it's not taking people's jobs.
It's adding to...
It's adding complexity and workload.
Well, yeah, for sure.
Absolutely.
So the, the, the, the,
the standard example would be
something along the lines of this
is it's not costing artists
their jobs because,
because I can make a
piece of art for my blog
because I can never afford to
pay that artist to do it anyway.
So now I'm just putting art where there
never was going to be any to begin with.
Right.
That, that's the way the
argument is structured.
There's something that happened that I
think the point that is being missed,
is being missed here is that
there's like a, there is a,
basically there's a subtractive
trickle up effect that
happens where you have,
you have the ability to,
you have artists that
are getting paid now,
but in order to train the AI, and I'm
going to use my wife as an example.
She has a website where, where's
with her entire art portfolio in it.
The big, one of the biggest jobs she's
ever gotten was a few years ago.
This is pre COVID.
She got a, she got a commission
from coach brands to do,
to do all of their
Christmas illustrations.
Wow.
So that's her, yeah, her illustrations
were on all like coach handbags.
It was in, it was in their
flagship New York store.
Wow.
It was all over the place.
Yeah.
And they, so all, and all of that is
on her website as part of her CV, uh,
because that's how you have to
advertise yourself as an artist.
Well, all that stuff has
clearly been sucked into
AI to train these image generation models.
She was never asked.
They just told, they just took, they just
took her stuff and train their model.
And so now, yes, you can
put that on your blog,
something that's practically a full ripoff
of some of my, uh, my wife's,
you know, uh, unique designs.
You could just generate that
out of something because
the AI generation doesn't make new stuff.
It only knows how to add a mimic.
Yeah.
And so there's this trickle
up effect that happens
where now I don't think coach would
ever come back to her and ask for
something else because why would they?
Yeah.
They, they paid her thousands
of dollars to do this work.
Now they can do it for pennies.
Well, it's exactly the same.
If we recall the, um, the
Silicon Valley business model,
which is give us all your stuff.
We'll pay you nothing and
we'll take all the money.
And it's worth reminding
everybody that this is
what the Microsoft's
artificial intelligence
CEO, Mustafa, what's his name?
Mustafa Suleiman said.
With respect to content
that is already on.
The social contract of that content since
the nineties has been that it is fair use.
Anyone can copy it, recreate
with it, reproduce with it.
That has been freeware.
If you like, that's
been the understanding.
There's a separate category
where a website or a
publisher or a news
organization had explicitly
said, do not scrape or
crawl me for any other
reason than indexing me
so that other people
can find that content.
That, that's a gray area.
And I think that's going to
work its way through the court.
Yeah.
Gray area.
So if I find a windows 12 somewhere
on the web, the open web,
I can download that and use it.
There's no problem.
Oh yeah.
It's freeware.
Freeware.
I tell you.
That's how, that's how
these people really think.
If, if I, you know, if I hear the, the,
if I hear the comparison to
like buggy whip manufacturers
one more time, I'm going to lose my mind.
Like this is such a bogus argument,
but you know, I mean, and anthrop,
because this, I mean,
this is just fundamentally
different that you're,
when buggy whip manufacturers
go out of business,
it's because they were replaced
by other modes of transportation.
Like you, you, you may have
lost your horse and buggy,
but you replaced it with a car.
You know, this is completely different.
You lose, you lose your job as an
artist because there's no more art.
Yeah.
Well, the pendulum will swing.
I mean, come on.
Well, it won't swing back
enough to, it won't swing back.
The, the, the immediate
repercussion will be that
the only people able
to afford commissioned
art will be the wealthy and
no, but, and it'll just, just,
it'll gut everything below, you
know, the top, but no, just everything.
But notice that the only
things AI really does with
any quote unquote exception is generating
audio and video at pictures,
but maybe just visual audio.
It's not very good at much.
In fact, I was just thinking
about the entropy part.
You can see entropy in motion right away.
If you say generate an image and then
you say, no, change it and make it this.
It can't, it'll make it shit.
It always does.
You know, it's just, you have to just
use the same prompt over and over again.
Then maybe you'll get what you want.
You can't tell it to change this or
move that up or move that to the left.
So it, it's, it's entropy in motion.
It's entropy in motion.
Well, you know, Anthropic just
settled that big bookcase.
Well, it's just the beginning, baby.
Yeah.
And Dvorak's in that case.
Oh, is it?
Did he get, did he get a check?
Oh, he thinks he'll get, he
has 28 titles to his name.
He thinks he'll get about $7
and 50 cents for each one.
Because they said the,
the published amount was $3,000 per
book and that's, there's no way.
Yeah, no way, no way
that's going to happen.
And yeah, and that, and they're doing
it now with Suno, Warner Brothers,
Sony, they're, they're
all saying, okay, we, that's fine.
You can do that, but we want a piece
and it's very complicated system,
but there's a, there's
a, it actually, when you, before
you get your Suno result,
it has already hit another AI,
which is now checking to
see a tone, a vocal, lyric,
and it's making assumptions
as to who owns what.
Oh, it's trying to see if there might
be a claim, a claim that could be.
No, no, it's not seeing if
there might be a claim.
It's dividing up the money.
Oh, oh, it's people are getting,
just going to start getting paid.
Oh, they're getting paid now.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
And then pretty soon, Suno, you won't
be able to download if you have a,
if you have a free account and you may
be only be allowed to make one song.
And then if you are a paying user, you'll
be able to download five songs a month.
If you want to download more,
you'll have to pay more.
Oh no, it's the whole, it's, it's
Google just got dinged in the EU.
It was like, yeah, we think that you're
probably stealing copyrighted material.
Well, that's going to be fun.
EU are a bunch of douchebags.
Well, they'll get, I mean,
Google, they'll get out of that.
No, they'll pay, they'll
pay, they'll have to pay.
They're, they have, they
have the best position of
any of these AI companies
because they already
had publisher deals,
many publisher deals in place for
like news and that kind of thing.
They were already paying because they'd
been sued so many times before they,
you know, they
already had structured deals in place
so they can, they're just like, yeah,
we'll just do whatever we want.
Well, this kind of is a good time
to bring in the TTS conversation.
I listened to the one you posted.
I listened to the, the, the podcast you
linked to the Reddit text to speech podcast.
And I can see people listening to that.
I mean, it's not my favorite, but
I've listened to books that were TTS.
I've listened to lots of
different things that were TTS.
If they're spamming, you know, if they're,
if they're creating a hundred
podcasts, new podcasts
a day with all Reddit content, I
think that's a different issue.
But if someone just
made a podcast and it's
an ongoing podcast out of a Reddit thread,
I mean, I don't, I can't
see that as invalid.
The, there's a couple of issues.
No doubt.
So they, they're not always
creating tons of new podcasts.
Sometimes they're creating a
few podcasts with thousands
and thousands and thousands of episodes.
Thousands of episodes?
Oh yeah.
That, that podcast that
I, that I linked to,
that was a thousand episodes
only because that's our limit.
Wow.
I didn't scroll down the list.
I'm like, let me listen to this one.
Yeah.
It would have taken you all
day to scroll down that list.
You know, I mean, no, they're,
they're flooding the zone.
I mean, they, and that's, that's what
I think is really the danger here.
So I put, I sent Sam Sethi a clip for
their end of year show and, you know,
just the prediction thing.
And my, that was part of, that
was what my prediction was,
was that 2026 is we're really
going to, is really
going to be the AI, um,
come to Jesus event in
podcasting where I'm,
I'm seeing it all, all across the index.
So there's another, uh, here's
an, let me give you another one.
Let me see if I can cut
this link out real quick
to where you're putting
it in the boardroom.
I just want to make sure it works first.
And now I killed some of these.
Let me, let me grab this other one.
I've got, I've got a few
examples of this that are just,
these are just scratching the
surface of, of what's in there now.
Yeah.
Here's one.
I'll put it in the boardroom.
So there's a, there's a
Chinese characters right away.
Yeah.
So, so play that and tell me, tell me, I
mean, that's clearly AI generated voices.
I don't speak Chinese,
but it sounds that way.
Oh, it's those guys.
Okay.
You, you kind of have to get in, get
into it from it at the beginning.
It sounds like it's not.
And then it goes into what's
clearly like you hear the,
the auto tuned sort of down synthesized
voice, synthetic fingerprint, you
know, and this thing is XY, uh,
where's the, it's XYZFM.space.
Yeah.
And it has about 10,000 feeds in there.
So I, I did a little
translate on the characters.
Do you also feel that while communication
has become easier than ever,
genuine dialogue is increasingly rare.
Do you long for an open
space amidst the noise
of echo chambers and
fragmented information,
a place for free flowing conversation,
sincere exchange, a profound dialogue?
Terrace Plaza is that very place.
Inspired by the conversational
spirit of the ancient Greek Agora,
we aim to bring a relaxed
leisurely atmosphere to the
living spaces of modern youth,
exploring the vast landscapes
of thought together.
What does that even mean?
What does that mean?
It, it, it all links
back to this thing here.
I need to up their mic game, man.
That's no, I think that's the synthesized.
That, of course, you hear it.
Yeah.
All right.
So.
Yeah.
There's like, there's about
10,000 of those feeds in there.
There's, yeah, there's just, there's,
this stuff is just flooding
into the index and it's
going to cost, it's costing us money.
Yeah.
You know, it's, it's slow
because there's slow for every,
for every thousand feeds that
go in there that are,
that are junk that nobody will ever
see or touch or listen to or anything.
It's stuff that, you know, the index
thinks that it has to keep checking it.
Now, are these being submitted
by manually or by pod ping?
Can you, can you trace back to how
they were submitted into the index?
Yeah.
All different, all different sources.
A lot of them.
And, you know, I hate to say
this cause I love, you know,
I love the tech tech guys over
at Spreaker, but Spreaker, they're getting,
their system is being gamed big time.
Their, their advertising dynamic
advertising system is just being exploited.
Yeah.
You know, cause like that red, that Reddit
thing, if you, if you listen to it,
you get a dynamic ad
at the very beginning.
Yes.
Yeah.
I did hear that.
And it's just like the, the,
if you can get it, you're,
you don't have to get legitimate
traffic in order to meet
some of these thresholds.
You could stick a, you can stick
a podcast out there in the,
in the ether and it'll get
a few downloads a month just by existing.
Yeah.
You know, you don't, you don't have in,
and who knows where they're coming
from or what these agents are.
You already, you already deleted
the, the Reddit podcast.
I did, I didn't think I did,
but I clearly, somebody did.
Somebody did.
I, I, I, yeah, yeah, somebody did.
You know, I just, this.
Yeah.
That's all Spreaker.
It's tons of it is Spreaker.
We've just given.
Oh no, it looks like Spreaker killed it.
Oh, did they?
Yeah.
Oh, sorry.
We're really sorry, but the page
you're looking for can't be found.
Yeah.
So Spreaker killed it.
All right.
So they're on it.
They're on it.
See this, this is the kind of,
so I think we're going to have,
we're going to be forced
to deal with this issue because
it's going to overwhelm
us and it's going to over, this stuff
is going in, it's going into
Apple podcasts as well.
We need a, we need a,
um, a cartel meeting.
An industry-wide task force.
Yeah.
I like cartel meeting better, but
yes, industry-wide task force.
What are we going to do?
We need to convene the
podcast hall of justice and
get everybody on the
same page and go after
these, uh, interlopers.
Yes.
Yeah.
I don't know, man.
I don't, well, this brings me to, um,
there's sort of like, um, let's see,
there's like, there's,
you might call it like a, like a dark,
there's like a dark poesis that
we're going to have to get into.
We're going to have to deal with
as this stuff goes forward.
Because if you give them the
tools of creation, uh, the,
the mass tools of creation to what
are essentially a bunch of two-year-olds,
they're just going to start,
you know, pulling the
trigger on the cannon and it's
going to flood everything.
And it's going to make everything worse.
You're not going to be
able to find anything.
All the directories are going
to, are going to crawl.
They're going to be brought to their knees
as people fight what is essentially a,
a spam battle.
Um, so won't this kind of
fix itself for two reasons?
One, uh, so you can already see speakers
like, all right, this is ripping us off.
This is no good.
So we're killing that.
So that, so they're working on their end.
It automatically takes care of it
on our end and the AI companies,
they're just going to
be ingesting more of this slop and it's
only going to be to their detriment.
But that could take forever.
And, and the thing is like, they're not,
the entropy happens within the model,
but thing that keeps it from
happening as the models themselves
move forward is it's being retrained
all the, it's being guided
by, by an intelligence,
which is us by a real intelligence.
And so I don't see the, I don't
see these models collapsing.
They're only getting better, you know?
And, and so I don't think that
we can depend on, on like a, a,
a system wide model collapse
scenario to fix this.
I don't think that's going
to happen anytime soon.
And in the meantime,
we're going to have to deal with
increased costs, a worse product.
Yeah.
I think, I think next year
is going to be rough.
Well, the, and it may
be another year or two,
but eventually the
compute used to do these
things is going to have to be paid for.
Cause right now that's the problem.
The problem is it's just free.
Basically you can create slop for free.
Yeah.
I think you're right about that.
The, but you know, they, as long as they
keep kicking the financial, you know,
come up and down, then this
is going to be a problem.
You're, you're right.
The, if they really charge what,
but all you need is the Delta.
And now I don't know what they're
going to, and, and if the, if the,
if the models that are
available open source,
if those become good enough and
you could run it yourself and
then there's just not an issue at all.
But that also requires, you know, stuff
that most two-year-olds won't do,
you know, hosting it yourself.
I mean, if you can run it on your phone.
Yeah.
I guess.
Well, I mean, an outfit like
Inception Point AI, they would do it.
Yeah.
They would run their own, own service.
Well.
With an open source model.
If they could, if they,
if the quality was there.
Yeah.
You know, and who knows if it's, I don't,
who knows if it's going
to get there and I don't
know, but I don't know.
This is a mess.
It's a real mess.
Yeah.
It sure is.
I don't know how to fix it.
I don't.
I mean, I can't, I can't spend all day
long weeding junk out of the index.
So.
It's not feasible.
So what do we do?
Well.
I mean, obviously.
I've got an idea.
Oh, okay.
Yeah.
No, I'm, I'm, I'm, I'm all ears.
I've got an idea for starters.
So.
Shut down the index.
Just shut it down.
Yeah.
We're going home.
We're going to take our ball and go home.
Well, so I was in there this morning and
I was just thinking about this stuff.
I was, I was looking at
it and think that it
would be good to start by doing something
that I was really surprised
that we've never done before.
It's kind of weird.
Why don't we publish a
real time view, the,
all the feeds that have
been added over the last
24 hours as an open end point.
So you don't have to have
an API to hit it and
we'll just publish it and it'll update
every few minutes and people can just, uh,
build tools to build
tools against that end
point that will look for
signs that it's garbage.
Well, okay.
And then what do we do with these tools?
We flag it and then we just say,
okay, you flagged it with your tool.
We take it out.
I don't know yet.
That's, that's step two.
I don't know.
I just, I just gave you step one.
I don't know about step two,
you know, cause I, it, I mean,
there's lots of people who would
be, I think they would
have fun building a tool
and they may have ideas
for how to, I mean,
Spurlock's clearly already doing this.
He's got some sort of
secret sauce that he's made
that he can identify these TTS podcasts.
Well, you know, and this also
goes back to let's, you,
I don't want to hijack any topics you got.
No, this is, this is an important one.
This is, this is some,
this is a conversation that many
organizations should be having right now.
How about every single hosting company?
Oh yeah, for sure.
Yeah, for sure.
Um, so as part of the
new architecture and a
lot of the stuff we've been talking about
for the few, for the last few weeks, uh,
I started thinking of, you know, we're,
we talked
recently about move your, move your
podcast.com and what, what prompted that,
you know, this
all goes back to the discussion that we
had about James saying, well, you're,
you know, some of the podcasts
and the podcast index do
not match what the feed URL is
in Apple podcasts directory.
So we had a long discussion
about that and how
directory sync is hard and we exist just
a thumbnail sketch here.
We exist to take the directory
of podcasting out, I mean,
back from the hands of
corporate ownership.
So it's important for us to be independent
and not just follow what they do,
but they do have one advantage.
They have one major advantage, which
is the intent of the podcaster.
And when, and when that intent is clear,
meaning the podcaster
diligently goes to their Apple
podcast connect account and changes their
feed URL, when the intent is clear,
that system, it's hard to argue
that that system is not giving
us all the information that we want.
So, but that, you know,
that doesn't always happen.
People neglect their Apple podcast
connect account, blah, blah, blah.
So we came up with the idea for move
your podcast.com where you could,
where we can make a centralized
location, centralized, but open, open,
owned by the community and
run by the community where
podcasters could go and
signal that their podcast
has changed or that
they're the, or it's owned
by this entity or whatever.
So do some sort of, uh, attestation.
And, and we, we, you know, we've got,
we're, we're going to be able to do that.
We'll be able to do that with pod ping.
And I'm going to get, uh, Alex is going to
come on the show and we're going to run,
run that down pretty soon, uh,
here in the next few weeks about how
we can do that through pod ping.
So that's the idea for that
is underway, you know,
old Dave versus new day old Dave would
have already had a website built by now.
And we, I mean, we know we,
we'd be, we, we'd be done.
We'd have something, we'd be
rocking and rolling, but you know,
But new Dave is tired.
No, new Dave is like,
hold on there, cowboy.
Wait up.
Uh, maybe you need to give this some thought
before you go and just build something.
Why don't you let it set, you know, give,
give it, give it some time to, uh, to,
to bubble and see what ideas come out.
Cause there may be, cause your first
idea about the way to build something,
a lot of times is not the best.
So let's just give this some time.
Let's discuss it before we just fire
off and start building websites.
So that's what I've been trying to do.
Um, the, so we really need
to solve this problem
and I'm committed to
finding a good solution
for it, uh, for the
attestation of the creator.
I'm not looking for the
solution or the right solution.
I don't like, I don't, um, don't like
those words as much as I used to.
We're going to see, I'm going
to talk about in a second,
why that's not really possible.
Developers always want the one grand
solution to a problem and they,
and they get all ticked
off when people don't all join on
board with their one grand solution.
That's just, we're all guilty of that.
We all want the right answer, but it's
just, no, it's just not that simple really.
Uh, but there are, but
there can be good solutions
that get us most of the
way to where we want
to be to that end of,
and I think this is also strongly related
to the topic of, of spam AI slop.
You know, we've, I think we've talked about
before, it's probably been a long time.
We've talked about before about
the, um, the law of identity.
And what I'm talking about
here is what is a podcast?
Yeah.
And we know like James told us
on the, uh, on pod news today.
He told us what he thinks a podcast is.
No, hold on a second.
I happen to have that clip.
It's not there in, in Apple podcasts.
It's not there in Spotify either.
So therefore it's not a podcast.
Can I just say something about this?
Um, my nephew called me yesterday.
He's 27, I think.
And he's, you know,
he's, uh, Willow's son.
No, Tiffany's son, Julius.
Um, his name is Julius.
That's a cool name.
Yeah.
And he, uh, he's been doing
hip hop for a couple of years.
And of course, you know, he's not,
he's working somewhere that
he probably doesn't want to
work just to, uh, keep his
so-called music career going.
And obviously that's going nowhere.
I mean, he's got, he's got a following.
He's got fans.
They do some live shows, but
there's no money off the product.
If you're performing
live and merch, merch.
So he says, you know, I've been wanting
to do a podcast for a long time.
I'm like, well, you came to the right guy.
So, you know, I gave him my, my
three golden rules of podcasting.
And, um, and I said, so what's the plan?
He says, yeah, well, we're
going to put it, uh,
we're going to put it on YouTube
and Instagram and Spotify.
And I said, just on Spotify.
It's not a podcast.
And, and he, and he really
didn't under, he had no idea.
He's a smart kid.
I had no idea what an RSS feed is.
And I said, well, why don't
you look at pod home.fm?
Cause that's our buddy Barry
and he's local to you.
And he says, he's a
podcast hosting company.
He says, so what does a
podcast hosting company do?
And I didn't answer him right away.
And he says, do they, uh, do they
have like studios and stuff?
And I said, no, no, no.
Then when I explained it to him, he
said, oh, they're a distributor.
And it was really interesting
that I thought, you know,
maybe we are making the explanation
of what a podcast is too complicated.
I think actually RSS.com tag, one
of their tabs is distribution.
And there you just say, okay, I want to be
on Spotify, Apple, et cetera, et cetera.
Podcast index, et cetera,
et cetera, et cetera.
With a couple of that are defaulted.
So, uh, that's the battle
is that understanding
of how podcasting works
and why you want it
to be an RSS feed that's lost.
This is not a dumb kid, you know, but
then once I explained what it did,
he's like, oh, so they're
like a distributor.
They said, well, yeah, that's
actually, you can look at it that way.
I mean, does he have to know how the,
how RSS actually works or can he
just view it as a distributor?
Yeah.
Cause they, they do, they distribute
your show to, to the R, I mean,
essentially to the RSS feed, which is
a proxy for everyone else to get it.
Yeah.
That makes sense.
I mean, you know, I
think, I think this is,
this is another example of like the right
answer, the best answer, the
answer isn't really helpful.
It's just, you need to find a
metaphor that people understand.
Right.
And I think that, yeah, that's as good
as any, I think that's a good one.
Um, you know, and, but I
guess for our purposes, um,
yeah, Daniel James Lewis is
saying that people should
not have to go to Apple podcast connects.
They should just three or
one redirect their feeds.
Well, Daniel, the problem is that's been
in place for years and they don't do it.
You know, I mean, it gets some of, it
gets a lot of them, but if that was a,
if that was a system that could
ever work perfectly, it would,
we wouldn't have these
problems that we do.
And people three or one redirect their
feeds and you know, or, or whatever.
And sometimes they don't.
And sometimes they create
a whole new podcast
and they've got two podcasts
and this brings me to my topic.
So the, we talked about
the law of identity,
the law of identity says very
simple, A is equal to A.
So if you look it up in any sort of core
logic, then you might better, it might
better be expressed as A
is not equal to non-A.
So what you're saying is an
object is identical to itself.
So I think when we talked about this a
long time ago, we talked about the example
of the mind and the brain,
if there's anything different
about the mind and the brain, then
they're not the same thing.
So physicalist, a materialist
might say thoughts, your thoughts
are only purely electrochemical
processes in the brain.
Whereas like a metaphysical dualist
might say thoughts are
non-physical events with
cross domain effects in the
physical brain and body.
And so, and what, and the reason they
would say that would be that thoughts have
properties that electrochemical
processes do not, you know,
thoughts have the quality of
being about something.
Electrochemical processes
can't have aboutness.
So there's a thing that's
true of thoughts that are not true
of brain electrochemical processes.
Therefore the brain
is not the mind. So that there's your lesson
example of law of identity. So that's.
It's very deep, Dave.
It's very deep for a Friday, but I'm,
I'm, I'm clinging onto your coattails.
We're, we're getting, we're
getting, we're going to get there.
I promise.
I think, I think this is important.
This is very important.
Critical.
In fact, this is why I have
not built a website yet.
Let's say.
So another example would
be something like this.
Let's say that I have
a green Toyota Camry.
All right.
There is a hit and run
involving a green Toyota Camry.
Well, how do we know if the car accident,
if the car that was in that
accident is my green is,
is my specific green Toyota Camry?
Well, because you look guilty.
Yeah.
Cause I've got a head wound.
So we look for what is distinct and this
is just a natural human thing that we do.
We look for what's distinct
about my green Camry that
would identify it uniquely
as being identical with the one that
was involved in the hit and run.
So like something like a license
plate number, maybe it's got a
really unique shaped dent
in the driver's side
fender from the person's head hitting it.
You know,
passenger, the passenger side
window has a crack in it.
That's a particular
pattern that was described
by a witness at the scene.
So what you're processing mentally is
there is a class of objects known as
green Toyota Camry's that class of object.
It doesn't even have to be
physical in the real world.
It could just be like a concept or idea,
but there is a class of object that
you can conceive of that is that.
And what you're saying is how do
I find a distinct instance of a,
of a green Camry from amongst the class.
Okay.
So think about picking
from a criminal lineup.
There could be five people that look very
similar to the guy that did it.
How do you know it's this guy?
Will you instinctively look for
things that are unique about
this one instance of this
individual looks like
this one instance of a
person that looks like this?
So the podcast index database,
these are all heuristics, I guess.
Yeah, that's a good, yeah.
You can say heuristics.
Yeah.
Heuristics would be a more
general term for the,
for, you know, how to
identify more, you know,
things based on properties across a set.
But you, you could, I think the common
understanding would apply here to you.
So podcast index database
is built on the idea that more than one
feed cannot have the same feed URL.
More than one podcast,
excuse me, cannot have
the same feed URL. Right.
That's wrong.
That the identity of a
podcast is not its feed.
A podcast is a metaphysical construct in
our minds that is, that's, that's
embodied partially in an XML feed, but,
but the XML feed itself
is not the podcast.
Okay.
The, the main table in the podcast, the
main table in the podcast index database
that holds podcasts, quote
unquote, is called news feeds,
or you can just call it feeds.
Okay.
For a long time, I regretted
not renaming that.
I regretted naming it that.
And I, and I wished
instead I had called it podcasts, but
it's actually not a table of podcasts.
It's a table of feeds.
It is a table of feeds and, and,
and, but podcasts are something,
podcasts are something else.
You're rocking my world now, man. I'm
very, I'm very shaky hearing all this.
So you could have three feeds
that are all the same podcast.
Yeah.
You know?
Well, in fact, there's a lot of that.
Yeah.
So that tells you right there that the feed
and the podcast are not the same thing.
So the, the, the law of identity
says they're different.
So we, how do we know what is a podcast?
How do we know what the no agenda show is?
We, we know what the no agenda show
is because we just know it.
In your knower. You
know it in your knower.
You know it in your knower.
That's exactly right.
Yeah.
It's, it's, it's, it's in there
and you know that it's that
podcast without looking
at the RSS feed to make sure when you,
when you see that podcast or when
you hear that podcast, you know,
it's the no agenda show.
Same with power, same with podcast, pod
news, you know, daily, same with this.
The podcast
is a, is a, is a metaphysical thing that
we represent partially with a feed.
It's a construct, man. It's a construct.
It's a social construct.
Thank you for not saying contract.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
But this is important because we,
the re if you think about the
reason that Apple podcast
connect works the way it
does is because there,
this inherent assumption is already there.
The inherent assumption
is you have a podcast and
it's called now tell us where the feed is.
That's a, that's a critical point.
I think you have a podcast
and let us know where,
where we can find the audio and all that
stuff that goes into the feed.
But you start with the
podcast, not the feed.
Right.
Whereas we did it the other way around.
Yes, we did.
Historically so.
We started with the feed.
Yeah.
The whole thing started with the feed.
We started with the feed.
Yes.
Uh-huh.
So in order to fix this, what I
consider this a problem, you know,
in order to fix this,
we need to flip it back around.
And we try, I think we instinctively
tried to do this with the GUID tag.
Mm-hmm.
That's still wrong.
And it's not, I'm not
saying it's not useful.
Useful and correct aren't,
aren't, you know, the same thing.
Well, let me just draw
an analogy for a second,
because that's exactly what
the music industry did.
And every song, every
recorded song is registered.
I forget the name of the registry.
And it has a certain ID.
It's kind of like the, the GUID for songs.
And whether you get it on Spotify,
Apple, download, CD, cassette tape,
that's the identifier.
So the, the, the delivery
mechanism is detached.
Is it like an ISBN on me?
Yeah, ISBN, exactly what it is.
ISBN, which I think we, we discussed
the GUID as an ISBN very early on.
Yeah, right.
That's right.
We did.
Yeah.
And so you, you would have in, in there
again, it's useful because you could,
you can have this universal identifier,
but that only identifies the feed.
Doesn't identify the podcast.
If, if, if you're.
Oh, yes.
Okay.
I see what you're saying.
Yep.
If your RSS feed goes away, if the, if the
RSS feed goes away to, for no agenda, if
the no agenda RSS feed goes away tomorrow.
There's still millions and millions and
millions of episodes all over the place.
Yes, the no agenda podcast continues to
exist is still there in a, in a concept,
in a mental structure that
we all have in our heads.
That's why people went, you know, the,
the feed for the daily source code, I, I,
you know, it's all over the place.
I mean, there's people, there's
people who are trying to reconstruct.
Yes.
The feed, the feed, the,
the, the, the episodes,
but they're doing there
because they know that
there used to be this
podcast called the daily
source code and they're trying
to piece it back together.
Okay.
So, so I think that we need to, for,
for move your podcast for
this website service, this
web, this service, I think it
has to have as its core, uh,
sort of core building block.
The idea that the podcast stands on
its own and that the feed can move.
The feed can be that you can have three
different podcasts with the same feed,
or you can have
three feeds that are, you know, uh, three
identical feeds that are, are three,
uh, three podcasts with, uh, three different
podcasts with the same feed, or you,
you can have all different.
So the podcast to feed connection
can be many, many to many,
it can be a many to many relationship
and that gives you the flex
of that may be nonsensical.
And I'm not saying that like from
a coding standpoint, that may be,
that may not make sense,
but I'm telling you conceptually
it is the right approach.
And so if we allow any feed to be any
podcast and any podcast to be any feed,
even multiples
in both directions, we immediately get
rid of this limitation where we're,
where there's like, okay, there's this
one, this one feed means this one thing,
because that's where you
have to stay in sync between directories.
Now, again, I'm so, so what, so you,
what we're talking about
is creating some kind of
identifier, some kind of fingerprint,
some kind of unique DNA for
the podcast itself that
can then be associated with a feed
or any other number of properties.
Is that, is that what I'm hearing you say?
Yeah.
So there's, yes, you can have,
so the terminology I'm using is
like a many to many relationship
and they may, that might not even be
like the most ideal way to describe it.
Right now we say no agenda show is
this, or let's, let's say, uh, uh,
pod news weekly
review is this feed pod news weekly review
may have three feeds for different,
for different purposes.
Now there may, you're
breaking all the rules, man.
What happened to the source of truth?
This, no, it's there, but
we, this is the problem.
This is the problem where two, so we
have a, we have a podcast and I'm,
remember I'm defining
these terms now and I'm using, I'm
using them very strictly a podcast,
not a feed talking
about a, we have a podcast, something
like, you know, movie time with Jennifer.
Okay.
I just made that up.
Well, Jennifer from the movie time with
Jennifer podcast, she may not know,
she may have gone off and
created, she was at Buzzsprout.
And now she went over to
blueberry and created an,
and cause she's thinking
about moving her service.
Well, now there's two feeds.
Okay.
There's two feeds and Jennifer doesn't
know anything about podcasting.
She doesn't even know she has an
RSS feed and some, we identify.
So, so her three of ones are messed up.
There's not any, she's,
she's got something over here in Apple
podcast that still says Buzzsprout,
but she's now in blueberry, blueberry, but
she's not really committed to blueberry.
She may go back to Buzzsprout.
She's just testing the water.
Well, podcast index says
she's at blueberry.
Right.
And Apple podcast says
she's at Buzzsprout.
Who's right.
I hate to tell you, but the
answer is we're both right.
Yeah.
And that's just the,
that's just the truth.
I'm with you.
I'm with you because I see it all the
time, all day long, all day long.
We're answering these emails.
So let's just.
And there are people
uploading in both places.
So what we're saying is, and this
is interesting, we should come up.
We need to come up with a different way,
a different identification
system than the feed
because we've lost that battle.
Yes, I think so.
Yes.
I think, I think, I think, yes,
I think, I think that's right.
I think Apple podcasts, the reason it
has a perception of quality to it,
the directory, I mean, is because
people can go and tell Apple
podcasts where their feed is because they
can, they do been around for so long.
They, they, for the most part do.
They don't always, I mean, there's,
I don't know what the numbers are.
That's they can.
And therefore there's a perception of, of
authority from the creator themselves.
If we're looking for something that is,
if we're looking for a
way to do this in an open
way where the community
is providing this service
for podcasters to go
and do this, then we're
going to have to, we can't,
we can't even write a single line
of code until we come to terms
with this scenario because this
scenario exists all over the place.
It exists a lot, like you said, we get the
emails that, you know, I mean, I know,
I know that this breaks, I
know this breaks brains,
but we do get these emails
and this is the truth.
And there's people who are like, I'm
on Buzzsprout and I'm on Blueberry.
And we're like, which one is which?
And they're like, well,
I'm doing both right now.
And they're literally uploading
to two different places.
There is no, there is neither one
of those feeds is the truth, but,
but at the same time,
they're both the truth.
So we, we have to deal with this.
Well, maybe, okay.
Then the only thing that's wrong with
your scenario is the domain name,
move my podcast.
How about this?
Why don't we use podcastlicense.com?
Cause it infers multiple things.
It infers, this is a, a license
that I have on my podcast.
And so I need to register
it with podcastlicense.com.
And of course, also later
I can arrest you and
fine you for violations of podcast code.
But do you know what I'm saying though?
It was like, it has, it has to
be something authoritative.
It doesn't have to be podcast license.
I just happen to have that,
but it has to be something
authoritative that just like, you
know, yeah, it's, it's a
marketing effort basically.
I mean, you know, Daniel's saying nobody's
going to do, nobody's going to do that.
Well, they, they, okay.
Well, they, people, they said nobody
will ever, uh, expand, uh, RSS.
So, you know, don't, don't give me
nobody will ever do it or nobody.
It can't happen.
We've proved that to be not true.
You know, you, you can't, I'm not, I try,
I tried to preface this by saying
there is no perfect solution.
There's not, I'm not
looking for perfection.
I'm under no illusion that
perfection is possible.
Not, it's not possible.
We're not, we're, this is, this
is not what this discussion.
This discussion is not about perfection.
It's about how do we build a
system that does not treat,
how do we build a system that, that
is resilient against different
legitimate differences
between different
platforms, seeing different
truths about a podcast.
It may see, it may seem like a worse
solution, um, than, than what, you know,
what we already have, but I'm telling
you, this one's pretty messed up.
Yeah.
Uh, you know, I think people,
I don't think people,
I don't think people understand really
because we interact with the podcasters
so often when they email us to tell us,
Hey, there's something wrong with my feed.
Yeah.
The first thing I do is
I go and I'll look at
whenever I deal with these and you deal
with more of them than I do.
The first thing I do is I pull
up the API, I go to the page,
I go look at the feed and
I click the little iTunes link.
Yep.
Same.
And about 50% of the
time they're different.
Then if you go, if you go and
you start doing some digging,
we'll find out that what Apple
has isn't right either.
No.
So it may look from the
outside like this thing works,
but I'm telling you, it's broken.
It's all broken.
It's not just podcast index is broken.
Apple just happens to be
less broken than we are
because most hosting
companies and podcasting
consultants and that kind of thing,
most of them will push their people to,
will push their
podcasters to go and do the, and do
either a redirect or go to podcast,
Apple podcasting neck and update it.
There's otherwise it, I mean,
we, the podcast directories,
podcast index directory has been
around for five years.
I mean, like we, it's got,
it's got wrong feeds in it,
wrong compared to what the podcaster,
uh, where they are now they've moved in
that kind of thing, but not nearly as many.
As you would think, um, comparatively.
So, I mean, the percentage is not
nearly as high as you would think,
because most people don't most, honestly,
most people don't ever move their
podcast from one host to another.
Anyway, this, this is all, this is all
framework stuff that I'm talking about here.
I'm talking about conceptual
stuff that we need
to bring to the table for taking back
the interface from the directory for the,
for the open podcast
searchable directory from
corporate ownership to the open source
community, to the podcast industry itself.
And nothing I'm saying right now is,
is saying that here's how the
architecture is going to look.
I'm not saying that I'm not
designing an architecture.
I'm only talking about concepts.
So I don't, I don't.
So you could have a, let's
just say we have a place,
the podcast place and
every hosting company.
And I'm sure, I'm sure they might,
we could get them on board.
Oh yeah.
Would, would say, Hey, you need to
register your podcast with this website.
And on that website, you
register your podcast.
And of course there's an
authentication issue there.
You know, who owns what?
Um, and then in there you can put
in what you believe your feed is,
what you believe your
YouTube channel ID is, what you
believe your Instagram ID is,
all that different stuff.
Because you'd have to do that because
some people are on YouTube and say,
I have a podcast and it's on
YouTube and this is my channel ID.
Sure.
Why not?
And then because Rogan,
Rogan is a good example.
Rogan has an audio feed to think is megaphone
currently, but he has a YouTube feed.
This proves my point perfectly.
That is two feeds of the same thing.
It's not the same exact
content because you might
have a little bit different content here
and a little bit, a little
bit different content
in the RSS feed and the Rogan RSS feed and
a little bit different content in the Joe
Rogan YouTube feed or YouTube channel.
They're the same podcast.
Well, here's what I could do.
Um, I could next time I'm
on Rogan, I can say, Joe,
we have a central podcast registry.
Now everybody's doing a podcast
needs to put their podcast here,
needs to register their podcast.
It's an industry effort, et cetera.
Now would Spotify participate?
Doubtful.
But I think, I think this
should be run by, I want, uh,
my vision for this thing, this,
this, this thing that that's gonna,
this website, web service, my,
my vision for this is that
it would be truly jointly
owned by everybody.
It's not a podcast index owned thing.
It's, it's everybody has a hand in,
in its, in its, in its support.
Cause I mean, I think that
the hosting companies
would really like for something
like this to exist also.
They probably would.
Yeah.
Cause people don't understand RSS
feeds, but they do understand websites.
And if you tell them,
if it just becomes known place that
you go to make sure that your podcast,
I said podcast, the place
you go to make sure that
your podcast is correctly
listed and findable
in all the directories place you go is, you
know, podcast dashboard.com or whatever.
It will just become a thing and
people will just know to go do it.
And we can still do 301 to redirects.
We can still, we can still
do all that kind of stuff.
There are so many ways that
can break tons of ways.
We have people that have moved
their podcast seven times.
They've literally been on every
hosting platform and they're,
for some reason, they're still there.
Yeah.
And you can say all day long, well,
the podcaster should know better.
The podcast, the, the hosting company
should do a proper redirect and blah, blah.
Can't, you can't push this.
You cannot push perfection.
No.
On the, on a, on a, you
cannot push perfection on a,
on a diaspora of all kinds of people who
do not understand technology.
And, and, and that's got to
be the way, where this is.
So if, um, that's the framework
that I'm envisioning.
And if that's the framework
that we can build,
then I think that
circling back to where we
came from here, I think
that can also have a
beneficial effect fighting the AI slop and
the, and the garbage.
Cause now we've distinct, we've, we've.
Yeah.
That's a good point.
That's actually a very good point.
Yeah.
We've distinguished a podcast from a feed.
And so now we can say, is this
podcast, what is this thing?
What is this a real podcast or is
this just a feed of gar, of slop?
Right.
You know, cause there's lots of feeds out
there, but not all of them are podcasts.
Even, even a lot of RSS
feeds are not podcasts.
I mean, RSS feeds with enclosures.
A lot of them are, I'm,
I'm honestly beyond that.
There was a, there was a podcast.
It was in anchor, I think
early on in the index.
It was an anchor feed and
it had 20,000 episodes.
Wow.
That's insane.
Each episode was a, uh, text, a text,
a computer generated voice
replaying a chess match.
And it was, they were posting like hundreds
of episodes a day and it was like,
and it would
just be a computer voice saying, you
know, black King two, three, two, A4.
Each episode was really short.
Just one move.
No, no.
Each episode was a, it
was a complete match.
Kind of a cool idea.
It was almost like one of those radio
stations that just repeat the numbers.
They had the little number repetition.
Yeah.
They're not, of course we know the, yeah.
I have an example of that.
Yeah.
Like this.
India.
Standby.
3, 33, 33.
Marbalizer out.
Like that.
Yeah, that's exactly.
Yeah.
And, but it was, it was,
I mean, that is clear.
Just nobody's listening to 20,000.
It's just not, it's just not, it's silly.
So this, that's not, yes, it's got
an RSS feed, but it's not a podcast.
The thing I've always, the criteria I've
used for a long time now is for the index.
If there's a podcast somebody wants to
listen to, they need to be able to find it.
That's what, that's the criteria
for being in the index.
If somebody wants it, they
should be able to find it.
Yeah.
If nobody wants it, then I don't
care if it's in there or not.
Otherwise, what's the point?
You're so hardcore, man.
I mean, seriously.
What's the, what's the point?
If nobody, if nobody cares
that this thing exists.
Then who cares?
Right.
Then why does it, why do we
have, why do we have to have it?
Yeah.
I'm with you.
Dude.
Oh man.
Sorry.
My brain's a little fried now.
So, sorry.
No, I think we need to continue this.
We need to continue thinking about it and,
and everyone should just
take a beat and be quick
to listen, slow to speak and think
about, you know, it's a very,
it's a radical departure
from the way we've looked at what is
a podcast and identifying podcasts.
And I think you're right.
I think that it's needed industry-wide.
Rodingers podcast.
No, no, this, I know, see, Dan,
Daniel is, is so mad at me right now.
He is?
The point, well, I mean, he's, he's going
off in the chat room, but the, the,
the thing
about is like, this may sound like a radical
departure from, but it's really not.
That's my, that's really
my point here is sometimes
when you really define the way, when
you, when you define the way
something actually works,
it sounds like you're nuts, but you're
actually, but it's actually,
all you're doing is you're
describing in minute detail, how
the thing is, how the thing
actually functions in our head.
See, that's, that's what I'm trying to
do is I'm trying to say, how do we,
as people, how do we
understand what a podcast is?
And it doesn't start with RSS feed.
It starts with the show,
the idea of the show.
We think of the Joe Rogan podcast,
but the Joe Rogan podcast is multiple
different distribution points.
It's an RSS feed, a YouTube
channel, blah, blah, blah, blah,
blah, a video on Spotify.
It's these, but it's still in our mind.
It's all the same thing.
And that's what I'm describing.
And now I'm just, once you describe it,
then you can build something
that replicates it
more closely so that people
understand it more instinctively
rather than having to say, okay,
let me first teach you what an RSS feed
is and blah, blah, blah, blah, blah,
you know, like, so that's
what I'm trying to do.
Well, it's interesting because I, I
was just going through this today.
I need to associate all of
the focus on the family
podcasts with their publisher
dashboard on Godcaster.
Okay.
And so I'm, I'm trying to do this and I,
and the system freaks out
because I find, you know,
focus on the family commentary, the feed
the publisher gives me is omnicontent.com.
And there's a clash because in the
index it's feeds.feedburner.com,
which is a very old feed,
which basically just still exists.
Now these are very different and, and the,
and the one with their actual
omnicontent is marked dead.
I mean, there's a, it's unbelievable
the amount of problems we run into.
Now, which, which one, uh, the
omni one, is that the correct one?
Yes.
Okay.
They all should be omni,
but I can't even change them because
the omni one is in the database too.
Yeah.
And that, that's something
that we got to fix.
Yes.
So it's these kinds of things that
just like, what are we going to do?
What are we going to do?
So, yeah, well, I mean, we,
and we see that I'll tell you
another reason why this has become
hard is because what you end up, you
know, if somebody changes their feed,
you have, you have to be sure to move
the listeners along with it, you know?
So you, you gotta, you gotta, you gotta,
it's not just simply changing the URL.
No, you have to shuffle things
around and you have to make,
we have to make an internal
redirect back to the old
feed to make sure that
people who are still referencing the old
feed ID don't lose list.
Don't lose.
Right.
So, so, so in this specific case, just
index question, how do I do that?
We can't currently, how do I,
how do I redirect the old feed,
the correct feed to the old feed?
You do it with a merge.
Oh, I forgot about merge.
But that's not, it's,
that's a little complicated from when
you have two completely different
feeds because it's hard to get them both
on the same screen at the same time.
So I'm going to have to do, I'm going
to have to do some work on this.
Okay.
Yeah.
So there, there's work I have to do to fix
the already existing problems we have.
Yeah.
That are, that are different
from the aspirational
things that we're talking about now.
Yeah.
I know.
I just, I was just in a, I was in a
practical mode for a second there.
Yes, Daniel, it does.
The index does update on a 301 redirect.
The problem is, this is all,
this happens all the time.
The problem is podcaster is on Buzzsprout.
They're going to move
their show to rss.com.
They go to rss.com first.
They create a new feed
with the exact same name.
It's the same show.
It's the same podcast on rss.com.
Now they have two feeds.
They haven't put a redirect in yet.
The Apple podcasts still
shows the old feed.
So now we have two feeds and there's
no way for us to know that they're,
that they're the same thing.
There's not, there's no way to know.
So now we have two feeds and then Apple
pot, then, then they put in a redirect,
but Apple podcast is still not updated.
And because we have to
stay in sync with Apple,
with Apple podcast as best
we can, what do we do?
You got a 301 redirect saying it's over,
it's saying the real feeds over here.
And now we have both feeds,
but Apple podcast says it's the old one
because they haven't updated that yet.
That may take weeks.
It's a mess.
Yeah.
It's a mess, man.
It's a mess.
We should probably stop,
stop where we are right now.
And thank some people.
No, no, no, not at all.
Actually.
I'm just like, Oh man,
there's so much to be done.
So much to be done.
Okay.
Let's thank some people
who were boosting live
while we were in this very deep
philosophical conversation.
And I hope that, I hope that
people boost in with some ideas.
Yeah.
We got a Lyceum row of ducks.
Thanks for bringing this up.
A is a best premises
says Martin Lindescoe.
I love that guy.
Now this is interesting.
We got a 22,222 sats.
That is a row of really
beautiful ducklings.
From Wes from Linux Unplugged
in Jupyter Broadcasting.
Oh yeah.
Wes.
He's on, he's on, he's on the social now.
Yes.
He says huge props to
Oscar and the fountain
team for iterating on the
metadata problem in public.
To help the effort, we've
built a simple open
source metadata server
implementing their latest idea.
The RSS colon colon payment link
spec discussed in a recent episode,
which we're calling Boost Box.
The gist.
When sending an LNURL P split,
you post your JSON metadata to the
Boost Box and get back a permalink.
This link serves as a human
readable view and implements
the header protocol for
programmatic parsing.
Check it out at BoostBox.cloud.
Like it.
Nice.
And he has a sample boost here.
Let me see.
Let me copy this and I'll put this into
the boardroom so everybody can enjoy it.
I have not clicked it yet.
I will click it now.
Click it.
I clicked it.
Oh, okay.
Yeah.
Nice.
Well, that works.
Okay.
Beautiful.
Yeah.
Thank you.
BoostBox.cloud.
Demo API key is V for V me.
V number four, V number four, me.
Thanks for all the great work.
Go podcast.
The website BoostBox.cloud
looks like it has APM links.
For the GitHub.
Yeah.
Open API spec and the API documentation.
Good work, everybody.
Nice.
Thank you, Jupiter.
And thank you, Wes.
Yes.
Very nice.
Salty Crayon.
Triple three.
Any chance y'all could bring back playing
a V for V track during the boardroom?
Was thinking about that the
other day and how people
would discover this niche area outside
of the P2.0 tech stuff.
That's a good idea.
Yeah.
But ever since we went to an hour
and a half instead of two hours,
we just haven't gotten to it.
I can shut up for a few minutes.
I mean, I can scale it back.
I kind of like listening to you.
You're the only one.
Everybody else is asleep.
I love listening to you, Dave.
I do.
I really do.
Salty Crayon again.
Howdy, Dave and Adam.
V for V for that entertainment from
the Suno creation of the Index Awards.
Yes.
I'm glad you enjoyed that.
And with that, I hit the delimiter.
I believe you've got the
umbral back up and running?
I've got our note.
I've got our Albi.
Yeah.
That's what I mean.
Yes.
The Albi.
Oh, and Darren O comes in with 55-55.
Dave hurt my brain today.
Sorry.
But I appreciate the effort.
It's okay, Darren.
It hurt my brain is swimming, too.
I'm like, we can do cool stuff when we
think about these things differently.
We can.
That's where cool stuff starts.
I'm with you, ma'am.
I'm totally with you.
Absolutely.
We do not have any one-offs.
That's not good.
No.
But we have some monthlies.
I'll go ahead and do those.
We got Podverse, $50.
Oh, thank you very much, Podverse.
Let me give you a little-
shot collar, 20-inch blades on the Impala.
Nice.
Lauren Ball, $24.20.
Thank you, Lauren.
Also nice.
Thank you very much.
Mitchell Downey, $10.
Christopher Harabarak, $10.
Silicon Florest, $10.
Christopher Warren, $5.
He's a new subscriber.
Terry Keller, $5.
And Chris Cowan, $5.
Dynamite.
And then we got some boosts.
Let's see what we got here.
Let's see.
Oh, Lyceum, 1776.
We got, let's see.
Adam, you are the tour
guide of the Big Apple.
I think we read that one.
Oh, wait.
We already read that one.
Yeah, we read that one.
I went a little bit too early
on the time cut off there.
Let's see.
Did we read the one from C-Loss saying,
interesting that Dave is now getting
into the AI-assisted development.
2222, welcome to what everyone else
has been doing with Cursor, Windsurf,
Google, Anti-Gravity,
and Trey for a year now.
Never let the AI make
decisions how to implement
something and always read
what it did, please.
I know from experience.
C-Loss also said, can we get
the horny gay guy AI voice
to talk about Dave's
nuts and bolts, please?
No, I'm sorry.
That's impossible.
He is also not allowed to
attend the Index Awards.
He's been completely banned.
He's not going to be, I
figured he would emcee.
Gene Everett, Satchel Richards, 1111
through Fountain, he says, I love you guys.
I wasn't trying to get the Hive crowd
upset last week, but the truth is,
Hive projects are failing
hard in the past year.
There needs to be a plan.
Okay, Brian of London,
get your keyboard ready.
Yeah, there needs to be a plan in
place for a future failure with Hive.
Yikes.
I'm not happy about it.
People who came at me on Hive,
please stop and understand.
I'm just trying to be practical.
Hive token is down 99%.
What?
And chain projects are drying up.
I thought they had some kind
of soft fork or something.
Did I miss something?
Is Hive token really down 99%?
Well, let's take a look.
He says chain projects are drying up.
Hmm.
There will be issues in 2027 or so.
Much love.
Again, only pointing this out because
I think there should be a backup plan.
Gene from Armonk.
Oh, Armonk.
Yes.
How do you even check Hive token?
Just put it into chat GPT, man.
I have no idea if the Hive token is down.
I don't see it as a, I
don't look at that stuff.
Because Hive tokens I bought,
that was my exit strategy.
I don't see it.
It's going to blow.
Okay.
That was a mistake.
Yeah.
Let's see.
We got Dreb Scott, 10,000 sats.
Says, go podcasting.
Thank you, Dreb.
Oh, we got the delimiter,
16,515 through Fountain.
Ooh, there he is.
He said, CompStrip Blogger, he
says, howdy, Dave and Adam.
I'd like to recommend
my new YouTube channel.
Oh, the AI Wizard.
Yes, the AI Wizard.
Just go to YouTube and
search for AI Arch Wizard,
whereby there is no space
between Arch and Wizard.
Or go to URL HTTPS colon slash slash
www.youtube.com slash at symbol AI-Arch Wizard.
It's showing how to get
the most out of AI tools.
No politics.
Four vids already.
Fifth next week will be
about Agent Mode in Atlas.
Voice over by Lady Vox from Alaska,
so it's pleasant to listen to.
Yo, CSB.
Yeah.
So I went to episode number four
because he said, please like it.
I'm like, okay, I'll check it out.
And the first three minutes is Lady
Vox proving that she's not AI.
It's like, you need to do that.
You know, I never, I couldn't listen past
all that to get to the actual contents.
Like, it's okay.
I trust you.
It's not AI.
Just tell me I'm not AI is good.
The AI channel, the AI tools
and tips channel using not AI,
that seems counterintuitive.
I'm just saying.
Just saying.
Yeah.
Don't worry.
We're not AI.
So that was it.
We're done?
We're done for the- That's it.
Wow.
That's it.
Nah, it's a bit, it's
affordability crisis, man.
Seriously.
That's what's happening here.
Well, we hope that you will
continue to- Ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh.
Stop the show.
What happened?
Listening to podcast,
from Mitchell Downey.
Listening to podcasting 2.0
live on Podverse Alpha Web.
Ooh, Alpha Web, Alpha Web.
Is this the alpha of the long-awaited
next-generation Podverse?
I believe it is.
I clicked on it, and it says, warning,
this is an alpha version of the website.
Oh.
Can you give out that URL,
or is that still secret?
No, he linked to it.
He linked to it on the podcast index.
Oh, I haven't seen it yet.
Oh, cool.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Oh, excellent.
All right, Mitch.
We've been waiting for him to
reemerge, and here he comes.
He's slowly coming out of the ooze.
Developer ooze.
Like the ascent of man poster
is dripping off of him, yeah.
All right, everybody.
Thank you very much for
attending the board meeting.
Boardroom, you are dismissed.
We appreciate it.
Have a great weekend.
If you'd like to support
the podcast index and
help us out with all of these crazy ideas,
we accept all forms of value for
value, time, talent, treasure.
Find us on the Mastodon
podcastindex.social.
If you need an account, you don't have a
Mastodon account, we'll happily help you.
Just email us, adam at podcastindex.org,
davidpodcastindex.org.
You can always go to podcastindex.org
and scroll down to the bottom.
Big red donate button.
Support us with some fiat fun coupons, some
PayPal, or boost us as hard as you can.
Thepodcasthallofjustice.com.
Boost us harder, everybody.
All right, brother Dave.
Have a great weekend.
You too, bro.
Everybody else, have a good one.
We'll be back Friday once
again for Podcasting 2.0.
You have been listening to Podcasting 2.0.
Visit podcastindex.org
for more information.
Go podcasting!
New Dave is tired.